You're Old Now
（海崎(かいざき)のあくび）
（海崎）ん？ 手紙？
A letter?
Kaizaki-sama
（海崎）ああ 日代(ひしろ)さんだな
“様”って…
Must be Hishiro-san.
"Kaizaki-sama"? Really?
昨日の1000円かな？
The 1,000 from yesterday?
Dunno why she did this.
She could have just handed it over to—
わざわざ
こんなことしなくても—
直接 渡してくれてよか…
Thank you
for your help!
Hishiro Chizuru
〜♪
（海崎）日代さん
Hishiro-san.
Good morning.
（日代）おはようございます
あ… おはよう
Uh, hi.
あの これは一体？
Um...
What the heck is this?
昨日 お借りした1000円です
The 1,000 yen I borrowed yesterday.
Thank you so much.
本当に ありがとうございました
（海崎）じゃなくて！
That's not what I'm talking about.
Wh-What have you done to Hideyo?
（海崎）英世(ひでよ)に
何してくれちゃってんの？
It's quite... a curve ball.
何で こんな 変化球… ふっ…
I thought returning it normally
would be too serious and boring,
（日代）普通に返したのでは
まじめでつまらないのかと思い—
so I looked around the Internet for ideas
ネットで
いろいろ調べてみたら—
何やら おかしげな折り方が
載っていて—
and found this amusing folding technique.
"This is it," I thought.
“これだ”と
（海崎）
ぶふっ！ いやあ おかしい
Well, it's hilarious!
これ 靴箱で開けちゃってさ
When I opened this by the shoe lockers,
盛大に噴き出しちゃって
やばかったよ
I damn near bust a gut.
Oh, my.
なんと
それは とんだご迷惑を
I did not consider the consequences.
選択ミスでした
以後 気をつけます
My strategy was flawed.
I shall be more careful.
（日代）
英世は 折ってはいけない
"Do not fold Hideyo."
（海崎）ぶふっ… ん？
じゃあ ありがとね
確かに受け取ったから
Anyway, thanks for returning it.
（海崎）別に—
It's not what you think.
I just find it cute that a high schooler
“変わりたい”と 不器用に
健気に頑張っている高校生を—
is awkwardly but earnestly trying to change.
かわいく思ってるだけだ
妹みたいな感覚で
It's like watching a kid sister grow up.
Mornin', Arata.
（大神(おおが)）おはよう 新太(あらた)
Morning... Wait, no honorific, huh?
（海崎）
おはよう… って 呼び捨てかよ
Arata's easy to say!
（大神）“新太”って呼びやすいし
何なら 俺も“カズ君”とかでも
Feel free to call me Kazu-kun.
いや “大神”でいいわ
呼びやすいし
Nah, Oga's fine. Easy to say.
（海崎）どうせ １年後には
誰の記憶からも消えてしまうのに
Either way,
none of them will remember me
a year from now.
Wh-Why are your scores getting worse?!
何で 再試のほうが
悪くなってんだよ！
（小野屋(おのや)･海崎）実に 面目ない
We're truly ashamed.
Arata's scores don't surprise me,
新太はともかく 杏(あん)ちゃんは—
but I thought An-chan
would at least pass one.
１教科くらい
合格するかなって思ってたのに
何で 俺はともかくなんだよ
Hey, why don't my scores surprise you?
Because you always gossip
when we try to study!
勉強しようってのに いつも
くだらない話ばっかしてるからだろ
Uh... point...
いやあ それは…
（狩生(かりう)）苦労してるね 大神
Got your hands full, Oga?
狩生 助けてよ
Help, Kariu!
こいつら やだよ
すぐ 話が脱線するんだよ
They're the worst!
They keep derailing the conversation!
脱線？
Like how?
Like asking if you and I are go—
この前なんて 俺と狩生が付き合…
What the hell are you trying to say?
何 言おうとしてんの？
えっ いや この前の
俺と狩生が—
Huh? I'm telling her about how you asked
if me and her were going out.
付き合ってるって
思われたってやつを
And why would you tell her that?
（小野屋）何で それを
大神君の口から—
言おうとしてんの？
バカなの？
Are you stupid?!
（大神）ええ？ いや バカって…
（狩生）んん？
W-Wow, stupid?
I just thought you two should
get an earful from her, too.
ちょっと ２人
狩生から怒られればいいと思って
それ言った場合 多分
キレられるの大神だけどな
You're the one she'd be mad at, not us.
えっ なぜ？
Huh? Why?
He's hopeless.
（海崎･小野屋）ダメだ こいつ
Huh?!
Oga-san.
（日代）大神さん
（大神）おっ
先生が 委員長２人
職員室へ来いと
Sensei asked both class reps
to come to the staff room.
R-Really?
えっ ほんと？
あっ ごめん 聞こえてなかった
Sorry, I didn't hear her.
So you really are dumb.
やっぱり 事実
バカだったんじゃないですか
しかも 想像以上です
Dumber than I'd imagined, too.
Ouch!
（海崎）グサッ！
I was better when I was actually in school!
現役のころは
もっと マシだったのに
Actually, I can do better than this.
ほんとは もうちょっと
できるんだけど
（大神）じゃあ してよ
（海崎）へへ…
Then do it!
うるせえな
まだ その 本調子が出ねえんだよ
Shut up!
I just... haven't put my mind to it yet.
Would that make a difference?
調子の問題ですか？ これ
ねえ？ もう 吐き気するっしょ？
Right? Makes you sick, doesn't it?
そこまでは言いませんけど
I wouldn't go that far.
Oh, really?
（大神）言わないか
（海崎）大神！
Oga!
I am trying, you know!
（海崎）
頑張ってはいるんだよ これでも
Then try a bit harder.
もうちょい頑張ってよ
（海崎）ああ…
（小野屋）うん 私も頑張る
Yeah! So will I!
何か 青春？
Ah, youth.
But with math, they say that you should put
something down even if you have no idea.
（小野屋）でも 数学がな
分かんないけど 何か 書いて…
じゃあ 日代さん 行こっか
Shall we go, Hishiro-san?
あっ はい 大神さん
Okay, Oga-san.
“大神さん”って カタいよ
That's too formal!
“カズ君”でいいのに
Just call me Kazu-kun!
はい？
Huh?
俺 下の名前 “和臣(かずおみ)”だから
My given name's Kazuomi.
じゃあ…
Then...
カズ君
Kazu-kun.
Wow! You're the first person
to ever call me that!
おおっ 初めて呼んでもらえたよ！
（日代）そうなんですか？
I am?
みんな “大神”が
呼びやすいらしくてさ
Everyone says Oga is easier!
やったあ
Hurray!
（日代）
あ… そうかもしれませんね
They might have a point.
もっと 普段からニコニコしてりゃ
いいんじゃねえかな
I dunno, maybe try smiling a little more?
I've got to try harder to make friends.
（日代）私も 友達作り
頑張らないと
Please wait, Kazu-kun.
（日代）カズ君 待ってください
（狩生）むっ… うっ…
You've got it wrong, Kariu.
She was trying for a friendly smile.
狩生 違うんだよ
あの子 あれで
愛想笑いのつもりなんだ
（海崎）他意はない…
（狩生）はあ!?
She didn't mean—
Nobody's that bad at smiling!
あんな下手くそな
愛想笑いがある!?
どう見たって
人をバカにしてる！
She's clearly making fun of me!
Yeah, I totally know how
you feel, but I mean it.
いや もう ごもっとも
気持ちは分かるが マジなんだよ
新太君 日代さんと仲いいの？
Arata-kun, are you friends with Hishiro-san?
いや ちょこっと話す程度だけど
Nah, we just talk sometimes.
（小野屋）ええ？ フォローして
あげてて？ 優しいんだ
And you're still covering for her?
You're so nice.
（海崎）あっ いや そんな
Oh, nah...
（小野屋）
そういえば この前 食堂で…
Come to think of it,
the other day at lunch, you loaned her...
Don't forget to write your name
on the record sheet.
（宇佐(うさ)）
記録用紙に 名前書いとけよ
（海崎）
う… 運動とか いつぶりだろう
National Fitness Test Averages
When did I last exercise?
Crap.
やべえ
Girls start with the 50m dash.
Guys start with the handball toss.
（天津(あまつ)）女子は
50メートル走からやるわよ
（宇佐）
男子は ハンドボール
投げからやるぞ
Amatsu-sensei, could you not stand so close?
（宇佐）天津先生
ちょっと離れてくれませんかね？
If we shout over each other,
nobody will hear us.
声 かぶっちゃって
指示 通らないじゃないですか
（天津）宇佐先生
声 バカでかいから 大丈夫ですよ
Usa-sensei, your voice is stupid loud,
so I'm sure it'll be fine.
ご不満なら
そちらが移動してくださいよ
If you've got a problem, move yourself.
４組担任の宇佐先生
Class 4's homeroom teacher, Usa-sensei,
was Amatsu-sensei's senior in college.
天津先生と同じ大学で
先輩だったらしい
へえ 仲良さそうだな
Oh? They're pretty close, huh?
えっ どこが？
Huh? How so?
Oga, you really suck at this stuff.
（海崎）大神
ほんとダメな こういうの
出席番号順で—
Let's go in order of roll number.
Starting with Asaji.
朝地(あさじ)から
（朝地）はい
Here!
Set a record!
（宇佐）記録 狙ってけよ
（朝地）
えっ？ がっ 頑張ります
Huh? I... I'll try.
45 meters!
（男子生徒）45メートル！
Okay. Thanks.
はーい ありがとう
（海崎）
あ… 高３男子の平均は…
What's the average for third-year boys?
28メートル？
28 meters?!
（海崎）いきなり
好記録出しすぎだろう 朝地君
Way too high a record
to start with, Asaji-kun!
Well, the dude is well built.
ガタイ いいもんなあ
（犬飼(いぬかい)）むっ…
Kids these days are in great shape.
Wish I was, too.
（海崎）最近の子は
体型カッコよくて うらやましいな
Next, Inukai!
次 犬飼
Here.
（犬飼）はい
Good luck!
（朝地）頑張って
Are you trying to kill me?!
（海崎）怖(こえ)え！
どこに投げてるんだよ アキ
Where are you aiming, Aki?
よそ見してるやつがいたから—
I saw a guy not paying attention,
“ちゃんと見てないと危ないぞ”
って教えてやろうと思って
so I figured I'd teach him that
looking away can be dangerous.
（朝地）口で言いなよ
（犬飼）ふん
Maybe use your words instead?
（海崎）
何 あいつ… 怖え
What's with that guy? He's terrifying!
（宇佐）
犬飼 ちゃんとやれ
Do it right, Inukai!
Next, Oga!
（宇佐）次 大神
（大神）はい！
Yo!
Inukai-kun threw that really hard, too.
（海崎）犬飼君も
あんな強烈なボール 投げたり—
今のところ みんな
平均超えてきてんだけど—
So far, both guys have been
far above average.
Is this national average even accurate?
そもそも この全国平均って
本当だろうか
とうっ！
（男子生徒）２メートル
Two meters!
You never change, Oga.
大神は相変わらずだな
勉強ばっかしてないで
たまには 運動もな
Maybe take a break from studying
and work out?
Don't be mean, Sensei!
ひどいな 先生まで！
しょうがないじゃん
生まれ持った運動センスがさあ！
What can I do?
I wasn't born athletic!
（大神）はあ…
（宇佐）次 海崎
Next, Kaizaki!
（海崎）ふふっ
うん？ あれかな？
Oh, what's this?
大神君は 運動のほうは
ちょーっと苦手なのかな？
Looks like you aren't so good at sports.
Oh, shut up!
うるさいな！
自分は どうなんだよ
Let's see how you do! Go throw!
早く投げろよ！
I was always pretty decent at this stuff.
（海崎）
運動神経は 割といいほうだった
ド田舎育ち なめんなよ！
I grew up in the country!
I'll show these wimpy city kids...!
この もやし都会っ子どもが！
What's wrong, Kaizaki?
（宇佐）どうした 海崎！
One meter!
１メートル
M-My shoulder won't rotate!
（海崎）かっ 肩が回らない
What the...
何だ これ？
俺 いつの間に—
When did I get this stiff?
こんな 肩 ガッチガチに
大丈夫か？
You okay?
I... I will be.
（海崎）だっ 大丈夫です
Adults need to warm up first,
（海崎）大人って
急に動いたら危ないんだな
or they'll hurt themselves.
体 痛める
Y-You okay, Kaizaki-kun?
かっ 海崎君 大丈夫？
俺 保健委員だけど
保健室 案内しようか？
I'm the health rep.
Want me to take you
to the nurse's office?
放っといてやれよ ノブ
つばつけときゃ 治る
Leave him be, Nobu.
He'll be fine if he puts some spit on it.
それは こういう時に言う
セリフじゃないよ アキ
Aki, I don't think that works
for shoulder injuries.
おっ お構いなく
Don't worry about me. I'll be fine.
Really? But if you need anything, just ask.
（朝地）そう？ 困ったら言ってね
女子か
Are you a girl?
（海崎）はあ 情けな…
Pathetic...
1st Throw Records
Oga: 2m
Kaizaki: 1m
Arata-kun, not only are you stupid,
you also suck at sports?
新太きゅんは
おバカなのに—
運動もダメなのかなー？
Shut up. I'm not like you.
うっせ 違うわ
若いくせに情けねえ大神と
一緒にすんな
You're too young to be as bad as you are.
年はタメじゃん
We're the same age!
何言ってんの？ くくくっ
Don't be ridiculous!
（夜明(よあけ)）ふふっ ふふふっ
What is it, Yoake?
どうした？ 夜明
Oh, nothing.
いえ 何でもないです
くふっ ふふっ
On your marks!
（天津）よーい
（日代）４コース ７秒38
Lane 4, 7.38 seconds.
（女子生徒）３コース ８秒22
Lane 3, 8.22 seconds!
You're fast, Rena-chan!
玲奈(れな)ちゃん 速いね
Thanks.
どうも
（海崎）へえー 狩生 速(はえ)え
Huh...
Kariu's fast!
（大神）
狩生は 運動神経 すっごくいいよ
She's really athletic, yeah.
大神と違って？
Unlike you?
（大神）泣くよ？ そろそろ
You're gonna make me cry.
ああ でも 次の子 見てて
But watch the next girl.
（海崎）ん？ どの子？
Which one?
（大神）一番手前の子
Closest to us.
On your marks!
（天津）よーい
４コース ６秒78
Lane 4, 6.78 seconds.
（海崎）速っ！
So fast!
right?
でしょ？ 玉来(たまらい)さん
めちゃくちゃ 運動神経いいんだ
Tamarai-san's crazy athletic.
（大神）
バレー部のキャプテンなんだって
She's the volleyball team captain.
And Kariu's the vice captain.
んで 狩生が
副キャプテンだって聞いた
I'm on the volleyball team!
（狩生）バレー部です
へえ… それはまた つらいな
Bet that's rough for her.
Huh?
Rena!
（玉来）
れーな！ どうだった？
How'd you do?
I knew it! You're really fast!
あっ やっぱり すごい速い
But really slow compared to you.
ほのかに比べたら
だいぶ遅いけどね
Oh, come on.
そんな 別に
人と比べなくたっていいじゃん
You don't have to compare yourself to others!
I can't help being competitive.
I always want to be first.
あたしは こういう勝負事は
一番になりたいたちなの
そっか
なんか ごめんね
Oh... I'm sorry.
謝んないでよ
余計 ムカつくから
Don't apologize! That's even more irritating!
“ムカつく”とか—
"Irritating"?
Don't say stuff like that!
（玉来）面と向かって言わないでよー
（狩生）うっ！ おい 乳！
Get your boobs off me!
Looks like Kariu-san
and Tamarai-san get along okay.
狩生さんと玉来さん 別に
仲が悪いわけじゃなさそうだな
え？ うん 何で？
Why wouldn't they?
They even eat lunch together.
Didn't Kariu say that the other day?
狩生 お昼は玉来さんと食べるって
言ってたじゃん
Oh, right.
そっか
Rivals aren't always enemies, huh?
（海崎）ライバル イコール
仲が悪いってわけじゃないもんな
にしても…
Even so...
...two girls cuddling sure is nice!
It's a sight for sore eyes!
おなご同士が
キャッキャしとる姿は ええなあ
目の保養じゃのう
これぞ 合法ＪＫ
This is what having legal high school girls—
（犬飼）おい
Hey!
お前 今 タマのこと
エロい目で見てただろ
You were just leering at Tama, weren't you?
えっ？ はっ ちょっと
いたたたたっ！
O-O-Ow!
（朝地）アキ！
Aki!
ごめんね 海崎君
I'm sorry, Kaizaki-kun.
こいつ タマちゃんのことになると
すぐ熱くなっちゃうところがあって
He just gets awfully worked up
where Tama-chan's concerned...
ほんと ごめん
I'm really sorry.
（海崎）はあ… タマちゃん？
"Tama-chan"?
Tamarai-san.
玉来さんだよ
あの２人と玉来さん—
Those two and Tamarai-san
have known each other since kindergarten.
幼稚園のころからの
幼なじみなんだって
へえ
んで 玉来さんと犬飼君が—
Oh...
And Tamarai-san and Inukai-kun
are going out, or something?
付き合ってるとか そういうこと？
さあ？
Dunno.
（海崎）
お前に聞いた俺がバカだったよ
It was dumb to even ask you.
Um...
（日代）あの
あの…
Um...
You, the redhead who ran 7.38 seconds.
タイム ７秒38だった 赤毛の人
はっ!? 何？
Huh?
What? You were talking to me?
あたしのこと 呼んでたの？
名前 呼べばいいじゃん！
Use my name!
わざわざ タイム覚えてるとか
何なの？ 嫌み？
Why would you remember my time?
Spite?!
嫌み？ なぜですか？
Spite? How so?
It's a pretty good time.
タイム かなり速いと思いますけど
As for your name, I'm sorry.
お名前は すみません
分からないので呼べませんでした
I don't know it, so I couldn't use it.
（狩生）えっ うそでしょ？
You're kidding.
We were on the class rep
committee all of last year.
去年 ずっと
委員会 一緒だったじゃん
I was the Class 1 rep...
あたし
１組の委員長だったんだけど
This girl!
（狩生）この女！
Sorry, but I just don't remember it.
すみませんが
記憶にありませんので—
お名前 伺ってもいいですか？
Would you tell me your name?
何なの？ この勝ち誇ったような
バカにしたような笑いは！
What the...?
What's with this mocking, victorious smirk?!
Am I not even worth remembering?
あたしごとき
覚える価値もないってこと？
Kariu.
（狩生）狩生よ 狩生玲奈
Kariu Rena.
It's my pleasure, Hishiro Chizuru-san.
よろしくね 日代千鶴(ちづる)さん
I'll remember.
覚えました
And thank you.
よろしくお願いします
It's almost my turn.
私 そろそろ 順番が来るので—
測定係を
交代してもらいたくて—
I spoke to you because I need you
to take over stopwatch duty.
それで 声を掛けたんです
ああ そう
Oh.
でも 何で 私に？
But why me?
You were standing nearby.
手近な所に立っていたので
（狩生）マジ… この女！
Is this girl for real?
On your marks!
（天津）よーい
I never imagined she wouldn't
even remember my name.
（狩生）まさか
名前も覚えてもらえてないなんて
１人でライバル視してる
あたしが—
And here I thought we were rivals.
I'm a fool.
バカみたいじゃん
（宇佐）
次 50メートル走 やるぞ
Okay, we're doing 50m sprints next.
移動！
Move out!
Yoake-san.
夜明さん 記録見せて
Can I see your chart?
Go ahead.
どうぞ
What the? It's like you deliberately
scored the average.
（海崎）
何？ この狙ったかのような平均値
I'm surprised you can even manage that.
つーか よく平均値まで
持っていけるな
僕 ここ２年は
高校生やってたんで
This is my second year as a student.
I'm not out of shape, like you are.
運動不足じゃないですもん
Well, getting that rusty body
back in shape is part of ReLIFE.
（夜明）まあ
そのなまった体の改善も—
リライフの一環ってわけです
But you'd better remember that your body
isn't young before you hurt yourself.
ただ 自分の体が
若くないってことは—
自覚したほうがいいです
ケガしますよ
周りの若さにつられて
張り切っちゃう気持ちも—
I know the youth around you
gets you all fired up.
分かりますけどね
But you're old now.
もう オッサンなんですから
うっ うるせ！
27は まだオッサンじゃねえ
Shut up! Twenty-seven isn't that old!
自分で言うのはアリでも…
Unless I say it myself!
But you don't want others to say so?
人からは言われたくない
難しいお年ごろですね
You're at a delicate age, huh?
あと さっき 女の子たちを
いやらしい目で見てたでしょ
And you were actually leering
at those girls, right?
犬飼君に締められてましたけど
Inukai went after you for it.
恋愛は止めませんけど
犯罪は勘弁してくださいね
We won't stop love,
but please... no crimes.
（海崎）ふんっ ねえよ
（夜明）ふふっ
I wouldn't!
If I don't warm up,
（海崎）準備運動しないと
さっきのボール投げみたいになる
it'll be a repeat of the ball mess.
下手したら
途中で 足 つるし—
I might even get a cramp...
And, in the worst-case scenario,
snap my Achilles tendon.
最悪 アキレスけん
切れそうだからな
For real.
ガチで
Ready!
（宇佐）よーい…
（海崎）ん？ 視界に
誰も入ってこないってことは—
I don't see anyone in front...
俺 一番前か
I'm in the lead?
なんだ 意外に走れ…
Cool, I can still run—
ひっ！ ぐうっ！
（海崎）がはっ あぐっ ぐあっ！
Kaizaki!
海崎ーっ！
I... I remember this...
（海崎）いっ いたわ
幼稚園とか小学校とかの
運動会で—
At kindergarten or grade school
sports festivals,
there are dads
who get all fired up to run
張り切って走るんだけど—
体 ついていかなくて
派手にこけちゃう—
but lose their balance
and fall flat on their faces.
お父さん… いたわ
Like I just did.
Are you okay, Kaizaki-kun?
大丈夫？ 海崎君
ああ… 朝地君
A-Asaji-kun...
うん 大丈夫
I'm fine...
（朝地）グロッ！
それ 大丈夫じゃないよ
Damn, that's gory! You're not fine!
I'll take you to the
nurse's office. Get on.
保健室まで運ぶよ 乗って
（海崎）いや…
いやあ ほんと 大丈夫なんで
Uh, but...
I'm really okay...
（朝地）どう見ても
大丈夫じゃないでしょ？
You clearly aren't okay! Come on!
ああ もう！
（海崎）あっ… ひいっ！
（朝地）宇佐先生
保健室 行ってきます
Usa-sensei, we'll be in the nurse's office.
（海崎）
ああっ 朝地君 下ろして！
A-Asaji-kun! Put me down!
Don't worry, I'm strong enough!
大丈夫だよ
俺 力はあるから！
そうじゃない！
そうじゃないよね！
That's not the problem!
（海崎）うああ…
10も下の野郎に お姫様だっこ
Princess-carried by a dude
ten years younger...
いっそ 放り投げてーっ！
Just throw me away!
Huh? What's up with the boys?
何？ 男子 どうしたの？
さあ？
Dunno.
Looks like Arata-kun
tripped and hurt himself.
新太君が こけてケガしたみたい
うわ ダッサ
That's so lame!
Mornin'.
おはよう
（日代）
おはようございます 海崎さん
Good morning, Kaizaki-san.
日代さん 歩きなんだ
You walk to school?
はい 駅から歩きです
Yes, from the station.
Me, too.
俺も
いつも１人？
Are you always alone?
誰かと一緒に登校してないの？
You never come with anyone?
Is that bad? Weird?
いけませんか？ 異常ですか？
誰も そんなこと言ってないだろう
Nobody said it was.
むしろ 俺も１人だし
I mean, I'm alone, too.
海崎さんは まだ
編入したばっかりですし
Well, you just transferred here.
That hasn't healed yet?
まだ 治らないんですか？
Uh, yeah...
ああ そうだね
もう あれから
だいぶ たつのに 全然… ん？
It's been a while, but it hasn't...
Is that the natural healing power
of a high school student?
高校生の自然治癒力って
そんなもんなんですかね？
M-Maybe so?
こっ こんなもんじゃない？
ひざのほうなんて まだ痛いよ
My knee still throbs, too.
I wouldn't know.
分からないです
走って こけたなんて
小学生以来 記憶にないので
I haven't fallen down since grade school.
（海崎）確かに
Right.
（海崎）
ああ そういえば—
一葉さんで ターバン
折ってみたんだけど—
なかなか似合ってたよ
Huh? Kaizaki and Hishiro...
（狩生）あれは 海崎と日代…
（日代）ほんとですか？
What the hell?! She can smile just fine!
何？ 笑えてんじゃん 普通に！
So what was that before?
今までのあれは 何!?
（海崎）おはよう 狩生
Mornin', Kariu.
Mor...
おはよ…
Good morning,
（日代）おはよう… ございます
Kariu-san.
狩生さん
（狩生）ああ そういうこと
I get it.
まじめなフリして
そんなやつだとは思わなかったわ
She pretends to be serious.
I didn't think she was the type.
But she acts nice around the boys.
男の前では いい顔するのね
The other day, we had a physical fitness test.
I'd explained to him before that he only looked
young, and inside, he was still twenty-seven.
Perhaps it wasn't easy to adjust,
even though he knew in his head,
“頭では分かっていても難しいのか
結構なケガを負ってしまった”と
so he hurt himself badly.
He seemed quite unhappy to have kids
ten years younger feeling sorry for him,
but it's helped him find his place in the class.
Oga Kazuomi
Kariu Rena
It's pretty clear now which
classmates he gets along with.
（夜明）だいぶ クラスで
関わる子たちも 固まってきたかな
It's been a month since he started school.
学校 通い始めて 約１か月か
It's not easy to form a community
that fast with high school kids.
高校生相手に よく ここまで
コミュニティを築けたものだ
One month since the experiment began.
開始から １か月…
April 25th
Nothing special happened today, again.
Still isn't fitting in with the class.
Still getting used to the high school experience.
I'll keep watch, patiently.
Nothing special happened today.
“今日も 特に
変わったことがなかった”
I'll keep watch, patiently.
“焦らず 経過を見守りたい”
April 26th
Nothing worth reporting happened today, either.
Nothing worth reporting
happened today, either.
“今日も 特筆すべきことは
起こらなかった”
April 27th
No change today, either
はあ… サンプルナンバー001と
002で こうも両極端か
Quite a gap between
samples no. 001 and 002.
He seemed quite unhappy to have kids
ten years younger feeling sorry for him,
but it's helped him find his place in the class.
He's had his share of mishaps,
but his ReLIFE appears to be progressing well.
He's smiling more than he did as a NEET.
ニート時代に比べて
笑顔が増えてきたかな
Still...
（夜明）でも…
And I think Kaizaki-san's
aware of it, as well...
海崎さんも 薄々
気にしているようだけど—
The immediate concern is...
当面の心配事は…
Kariu Rena
〜♪
NEXT EPISODE
（狩生）体力テスト
全部 ほのかに負けた
I can't believe I lost to Honoka
in all the fitness tests.
（玉来）ええ？ 玲奈は
勉強できるし うらやましいよ
But you're smart! I wish I could say
the same for myself.
（狩生）ほのかは 頭悪いもんね
（玉来）ひどーい！
Yeah, you're pretty dumb.
You meanie!
（狩生）あたしが 勉強
教えてあげよっか？
Want me to tutor you?
Fall
No thanks.
（玉来）いや いい
玲奈 スパルタで怖い
You're too Spartan.